《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
-东西在哪里？ -你去死
- Where is it? - Go to hell.
是你害死你自己的
You did this to yourself.
莎拉，如果你在听的话 我希望你已找到你的安全港
Sara, if you're listening, I only hope by now you've found your safe haven,
我利用了你 让你置身于所有医生的梦魇
I took advantage of you and put you in a place that's every doctor's nightmare,
莎拉丹奎迪 你跟她熟吗？
sara Tancredi. You know her well?
如果你把我调走 我就跟她很熟
I'd know her better if you get my ass moved.
-我会找典狱长谈 -“再一次机会”和“安全港”
- I'll talk to the warden. - Another Chance, safe Haven.
都是戒酒无名会 使用书籍的章名
Those are the names of some of the chapters in the book they use in A.A.
千万不要质疑我的话 我们是一家人，同归于尽也无妨
Don't make no mistake about it. We will be a family if it kills us.
那是你的地图？
That's your map?
-你的手怎么了？ -我爸爸也会喝酒
- What happened to your arm? - My dad drinks too.
我的肚子痛
My tummy hurts.
她需要吃药 两天没吃药会发作
She needs that medicine. She can't go two days without it.
凯西要被正式起诉了 帮助逃犯的罪名
Kacee's going into the system now. Aiding an escaped con.
-我会自首 -凯西要你继续逃
- I'll turn myself in. - Kacee said you need to run.
如果你被逮捕或是自首 蒂蒂会失去双亲
If you turn yourself in, Dede won't have either of you.
-迈克，我要这一切结束 -我也是
- Michael, I want this to be over. - That makes two of us.
现在都要靠 你父亲给你的东西了
It's looking at whatever your father gave you,
只是一把钥匙
It's just a key.
长官，恕我直言K 有个场合她可以派上用场
If I may, sir. The president, she could be useful.
总统女士？
Madame President?
我要你回来，保罗
I want you to come home, Paul,
但不能让这两兄弟流窜全国
But not with those brothers running around the country,
-卡洛琳K -请你逮捕他们，保罗
- Caroline. - Please bring them in, Paul,
之后一切就能恢复原状
And everything can go back to the way it was,
（印第安那州，伊凡斯维尔）
我是凯勒曼探员
Agent Kellerman.
保罗，你在哪里？
Paul, where are you?
-被你丢在外头，忘了吗？ -我今晚要在芝加哥演讲
- Out in the cold, remember? - I'm speaking in chicago tonight,
我会的
Yeah, well...
林克
Lincoln.
莎拉
Sara.
真有趣，你只有在 需要我的时候才打给我
It's funny how you only call me when you need me.
-也许说有趣不太恰当 -一切都可以结束，保罗
- Maybe funny's not the right word. - All of this can go away, Paul,
-真的吗？ -真的
- Can it? - Yes,
我是美国总统
I am the president of the United States,
请你回芝加哥 交出斯科菲尔德和柏劳
Please just come back to chicago and turn Burrows and Scofield in,
我向你保证 一切都会回到当初
I promise you that I will make everything go back to the way it was,
-我得走了 -回来吧，保罗
- I have to go. - Just come back, Paul,
我需要你
I need you,
你认为我们有机会平反？
You actually think we have a shot?
这要看你父亲交给你 什么东西
It depends on what your father gave you.
我发现他时，钥匙从他口袋掉出来 我不认得这徽章，你呢？
This fell out of his pocket when I found him. I don't recognize the insignia, do you?
不认得
No.
可是K
But, uh...
莎拉，现在有人 和我们一起合作
sara, we've got someone working with us now.
早安，宝贝
Good morning, sunshine.
睡得好吗？
How'd you sleep?
不如这样
I tell you what.
我去放孩子们出来 再替大家做早餐
I'll go unlock the kids and make us all breakfast.
不，我去找孩子
No, I'll get the kids.
-不 -我坚持
- No. - I insist.
不行
No.
我去找孩子
I'll get the kids.
我的护手霜可以 让绳子擦伤的地方舒服一点
And my hand cream will make them rope burns feel better.
行不通的
It won't work.
当然可以，瓶子上面有写
Of course it will. Says right here on the bottle:
-“舒缓皮夫不适K” -不，我是说这件事
- "Soothes skin irritations and..." - No. This.
行不通的，我有工作 孩子要上学
It won't work. I've got a job. The kids have school.
等这个调适时期结束K
We're all gonna get back to our normal routines...
我们就会恢复正常生活
...once this little adjustment period is over.
-今天有人会来 -谁？
- There's someone coming over today. - Who?
社区欢迎委员会的派蒂
This woman, Patty, from the Welcome Wagon Committee.
-打电话取消 -我没有她的电话
- Call her and cancel. - I don't have her number.
如果她来，我没有应门
And if she shows up and I don't answer the door...
她会发现出事了
...she's gonna know something's wrong.
泰迪
Teddy.
亲爱的泰迪
Teddy bear.
你必须离开
You need to go.
如果她认出你来K
If she recognizes you...
我不希望你惹上麻烦
I don't want you to get in trouble.
别胡说了
That's nonsense.
不麻烦
It's no trouble.
一点麻烦也没有
No trouble at all.
起床了，孩子们
Wakey-wakey, children.
你好，莎拉
Hi, sara.
我们既往不咎 现在我们目标一致K
What's done is done. We all want the same thing.
你没说你丢下她 让她等死
You didn't tell us you left her to die.
我当时只是在吓唬她
I was scaring her.
我会把她拉出来的
I would've pulled her out.
不，你想害我在里头溺死
No. No, you left me in there to drown.
不知道你能憋气多久
I wonder how long you can hold your breath.
-我们来试试看 -你需要我，你很清楚
- Maybe we should find out. - You need me and you know it.
你需要我，你很清楚
You need me. You need me and you know it.
为何需要他？钥匙在我们手上 我们可以查出用途
Why? Why do we need him? We have the key. We'll find out what it's for.
我现在就能告诉你们 钥匙的用途
I can tell you what that key's for right now.
那是私人雪茄俱乐部的钥匙
It's to a private cigar club.
在哪里？
Where?
芝加哥
Chicago.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：芝加哥
我们得快点
We have to hurry.
我们得快点，赖瑞 我做了坏事
We have to hurry, Larry. I did a bad thing.
我做了很坏的事
I did a very bad thing.
所有的加油站
All gas stations.
八十、三十、七十七号公路上
On 80, 30, 77.
我要所有的加油机 都贴上这两兄弟的照片
I want scofield and Burrows' pictures on each and every gas pump.
如果车子没油 他们哪儿都去不了
If they have no fuel, they can't get anywhere.
-长官 -什么事？
- Sir. - What?
我们可能得稍微 从斯科菲尔德与柏劳身上分心
We might need to divert our attention away from scofield and Burrows.
-为什么？ -逃犯之一刚杀了一位平民
- Why would I do that? - One of the escapees just killed a civilian.
是帕托西克
Patoshik.
有人看到符合描述的男子 从残暴凶杀案的现场逃逸
A man fitting his description was spotted running from the scene of a brutal homicide.
地点在威斯康辛州阿哥马
It happened in Algoma, Wisconsin.
离总统所在处不到四小时
It's less than four hours from the president.
连络麦迪逊的分局 叫他们派人过去
Call the field office in Madison and have them get some agents out there.
-我会通知总局 -我没说总局K
- I'll notify headquarters. - I didn't say headquarters.
你不听我的指示吗？
Are you not following direct orders?
我听指示，长官
Oh, I'm following direct orders, sir.
但再也不是你的了
Just not from you anymore.
现在起，一切都要呈报总部
Everything goes through headquarters from now on.
我可以走了吗？
May I?
什么事？
Yeah?
听说帕托西克的事了吗？
You heard about Patoshik?
刚听说
Just now.
很好
Good,
-杀了他 -拜托
- He goes. - Come on,
他有精神病 什么都不知道
The man is mentally ill. He doesn't know anything.
帕托西克曾当过 斯科菲尔德的狱友
Patoshik was one of scofield's cellmates for a while.
斯科菲尔德帮他脱逃 天晓得他知道什么
He's included in the escape. Who knows what he knows.
-这两兄弟依然K -现在先别管这两兄弟的事
- Scofield and Burrows are still out. - Don't worry about scofield and Burrows.
所以K
So.
我再说一次
Again.
杀了帕托西克
Patoshik goes.
把事办好
Take care of it.
你好，你负责划位吗？
Hi. Are you in charge of seating?
-对，有事吗？ -保罗凯勒曼探员，特勤
- Yeah. Can I help you? - Agent Paul Kellerman, secret service.
我要移送逃犯回芝加哥 我要你替我清空一节车厢
I'm transporting a fugitive to Chicago. I need you to clear a car for me.
-逃犯？ -没错
- A fugitive? - That's right.
可是火车几乎已经客满了K
It's just, we're already near capacity, I mean...
你要他和其他乘客 挤在一起吗？
You want us to rub elbows with the passengers?
-不是的 -好
- No, sir. - Okay.
他犯了什么罪？
What's he wanted for?
杀人
Killing people.
-天啊 -麻烦你了
- Good Lord. - Make it happen.
走，跟我来
Come on. Follow me.
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right.
你说了算
If you say so.
我们利用他 找到需要的资料
We use him to get what we need...
然后就甩了他
...then we dump him.
好
Okay.
我很抱歉把你牵扯进来
I'm sorry you got involved in this.
你能帮助我们K
The fact that you're helping us...
对我们意义重大
...it means a lot.
谢谢你
Thank you.
其他乘客不会有危险吧？
The other riders aren't in any danger, are they?
我需要广播通知大家吗？
I mean, should I make an announcement or anything?
你想造成大恐慌吗？
You want pandemonium?
-不想 -好，那就别广播
- No, sir. - Okay, then no announcements, all right?
不要让人进入这车厢 一切就没事
Keep everybody out of this car and everything's jake.
我经验丰富，从未出过问题
I've done this a million times, never had a problem.
好的
Yeah. Will do.
上来吧
Let's go.
前往芝加哥的乘客K
For all passengers going to chicago,,,
我们将停靠K
,,, we will be stopping at stations,,,,
五小时后就会抵达芝加哥
We'll be in Chicago in about five hours.
休息一下吧？
You wanna get some rest?
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
（伊利诺州久利特 福克斯河州立监狱）
布拉德
Brad.
你的脸色真难看
You don't look good.
我帮你找莎拉丹奎迪 你说好要帮我调到单独牢房
I helped you with sara Tancredi, and you were supposed to get me into Ad seg.
我试过了
I tried.
可是新的典狱长K
But your new warden...
讲都讲不通
...straight as an arrow...
但我可能有 比单独牢房更好的奖赏
...but I might be able to do you one better than Ad seg.
你透过那俄国女孩 找到那两兄弟，对吧？
You found scofield and Burrows through the Russian girl, right?
对，妮卡，怎么了？
Yeah, Nika. Why?
你也透过苏珊贺兰德 找到包威
And you tracked down Bagwell by following susan Hollander.
对，我习惯用右手擤鼻涕
Yeah. And I blow my nose with my right hand...
用左手擦屁股 那又怎样？
...and I wipe my ass with my left. What of it?
我背后有很强大的势力在撑腰 他们要我完成任务
I've got very powerful people behind me that want me to finish my job.
他们有办法对法院施压 让你快速拿到人身保护令
They can push the quickest habeas corpus proceedings the courts have ever seen.
现在这些文件 就放在负责人桌上
The paperwork's sitting on the right person's desk as we speak...
提出你的起诉过程中 所有违宪的部份
...setting forth all the constitutional violations in your prosecution.
只要盖个章就好
It's just waiting to be rubber-stamped.
你们要我做什么？
And what do I have to do?
只要找到那些逃犯
You just find those cons.
不过这次K
Only this time...
你要替我工作
...you're gonna do it for me.
低调秘密地进行 不留证据
Unofficially, under the radar, no paper trail.
我要一个心狠手辣 愿意动手的人
I need a junkyard dog who's willing to do the ugly things it takes...
才能够让逃犯就地正法
...to bring a con to justice.
你愿意吗，布拉德？
Are you my dog, Brad?
那当然
Damn hell yeah, I am.
真美味
This is delicious.
你说菜名叫什么？
What'd you call it again?
亲爱的派蒂 我阿拉巴马的阿姨叫它游民鸡
That, my dear Pattycake, is what my auntie back in 'Bama used to call hobo chicken...
一份鸡肉、两份香料 三份真正的游民
...one part chicken, two parts spice, three parts actual hobo.
真爱说笑
Oh, come on.
我知道K
I know...
传统早午餐 不会吃鸡鸭肉K
...fowl isn't part of a traditional brunch, per se...
但我发现瘦肉 可以当成开胃菜
...but I have found a lean meat can act as an aperitif...
唤醒味蕾K
...to awaken the palate...
感受更细致的味道和口感
...for more subtle flavors and textures...
例如K
...such as...
来了
Mommy!
南瓜肉桂面包 加上新鲜草莓和奶油
- Pumpkin cinnamon bread with fresh strawberries and cream.
天啊
Oh, boy.
你们是怎么认识的？
Now, how did you two meet?
教会
Church.
在我发生K
After my...
意外之后
...accident...
我和其他残障人士在当义工
...I was volunteering with some other amputees.
我家乡的教区 和这里的教会K
My parish back home did an exchange program...
办了交换义工计划
...with churches all over this fine country and, well...
上帝冥冥中 安排了我这乡巴佬
...the good Lord just saw fit to plop my country rump right down...
坐在我的小苏珊旁边
...in the pew right beside my suzie Q.
你就这样偷走她的心
And you just stole her heart.
我是个独臂强盗
I'm a regular one-armed bandit.
瓦勒斯太太
Mrs. Wallace.
泰迪刚买了台新脚踏车给我
Teddy just bought me a brand-new bike.
-就在车库，你想不想看？ -好啊
- It's out in the garage. Wanna go see? - Sure.
我们有客人
We have got company.
没关系的
Oh, that's okay.
不，这样没礼貌 柴克很清楚，对吧？
No, it's not. It's rude. Zack knows better, ain't that right?
你应该很清楚，柴克
You do know better, Zack.
一定要守规矩
You gotta have discipline.
如果没有父亲管教 年轻人可能会落到坐牢的下场
Without a strong father figure, a young man might just end up in prison.
既然你这么喜欢K
Since you are such a fan,,,
店里卖的三流蓝莓派 我就烤真正的派请你吃
...of Elaine's store-bought blueberry pie, I'm gonna bake you a real pie.
我是兰斯，我有毒瘾
My name's Lance, and I'm an addict.
你好，我不叫兰斯 我没有毒瘾
Hi. My name is not Lance, and I'm not an addict.
迈克
Michael.
你知道哪里有水喝吗？
Do you know if there's any way I can get any water?
楼下好像有厕所 我去看看
Yeah, I think there's a bathroom downstairs. I'll check.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不是针对你个人，莎拉
It was never personal, sara.
-战争无关个人 -对
- War never is. - Yeah.
莎拉
Sara.
莎拉，放手
Sara, back off.
-放开他，莎拉，莎拉！ -莎拉
- Let him go, sara. Sara! - Sara.
别激动
Settle down.
站住K
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
我总有一天会给你好看K
You get one of those. You get one of those. One.
趴下，动作快
Down. Get down, right now.
什么事？
What?
这三个人说 好像看到有人在打架
These three guys said they saw what looked to be a fight going on in there.
没有，好吗？ 让我们去芝加哥就是了
They didn't, okay? Just get the train to Chicago.
-需要我通知警察吗？ -照我刚刚的话去做
- Do I need to notify the police? - Do what I told you to do.
你检查车票，我看守逃犯 你们可以继续吸大麻K
Take the tickets, I'll watch the fugitive, you can continue to do bong-hits...
我不管你们在后面要作什么 你们不要多管闲事
...or whatever you do back there, okay? You guys mind your own business.
大家都懂了吗？
Everybody clear?
很好
Great.
请不要再来打扰
Don't interrupt again, please.
（小心）
咱们把话说清楚
Just so we're all clear...
要是她敢再动我K
...if she tries that again...
你要怎么办？
You'll do what?
留在车厢另一头就是了
Just stay on the other side of the car.
我不是针对你个人，保罗
It wasn't personal, Paul.
（福克斯河州立监狱）
这是我们的荣幸，派蒂
The pleasure was all ours, Pattycake.
这是什么？
Oh, what are these?
我K在重新装璜
I'm gonna do some renovations.
我在修补石膏板 找里面的钉子
I was just tapping the sheetrock, looking for the stud.
看来你已经找到壮男了
Looks like you already found one.
真是口无遮拦
Potty-mouth!
我们每周五 会举办读书会
Me and the girls get together every Friday for book club.
这周应该你主办 大家就可以认识你
You ought to host it this week, and everybody can meet you.
到时见
I'll see you then.
我等不及了
Can't wait.
在这里行不通的
This ain't never gonna work here.
去打包行李
Go pack your things.
我们要搬家
We're moving.
（明尼苏达州，班森）
如果你不阻止我K
Now, if you don't stop me...
我会一个人把它吃光光
...I am gonna eat this whole thing by myself, huh?
好吧，甜心
All right, sweetie.
听着，我们来做个约定
Listen, I'll make a deal with you.
记得我们今天 看到的旋转木马吗？
Remember that merry-go-round that we saw today?
如果你不吃东西 就不能去搭，好吗？
You're not gonna get a chance to ride it if you don't eat something. Go ahead.
可是我不舒服
I don't feel good.
甜心啊
Oh, sweetie.
来，我们走吧
Okay, come on. Let's go, all right?
我抱你
I got you.
再等一下好吗，宝贝 买单？
Okay, just hold on, okay, sweetpea? Check, please.
大家不准动！
All right, nobody move.
-莎拉 -现在别吵我
- Hey, sara. - Not now.
她还好吗？
How is she?
她想一个人静一静
Well, she wants to be alone.
我们拿到她父亲 锁起来的东西，然后呢？
So we get what her dad locked away with that key. What do we do then?
你也看到 他们如何处理我们拍的影带
I mean, you saw what they did with the tape we made.
他们会湮灭一切
They're gonna bury everything.
所以我们才留他在身边
That's why we're keeping him close to us.
他跟华府关系匪浅
He's got a lot of connections in Washington.
我们去雪茄俱乐部 打开她父亲的箱子
So we get to this cigar club, open her dad's box.
如果里面只有 一堆雪茄怎么办？
What if the only thing inside's a bunch of stogies?
我们还是应该 走一趟去查清楚
I think it's worth making the trip to find out.
-什么事？ -卡洛琳
- Yes? - Caroline.
保罗，你在哪里？
Paul, where are you?
你说你会弥补我 我要确切知道那是什么意思
I need to know exactly what you meant when you said you're gonna make this right.
-告诉我细节 -你在哪里？怎么那么吵？
- I need specifics. - Where are you? What's that noise?
我在火车上 今天稍晚就会到芝加哥
I'm on a train. I'll be in Chicago later today.
但我要知道细节
But I need to know some specifics.
柏劳和斯科菲尔德呢？ 跟你在一起吗？
Where are Burrows and Scofield? Are they with you?
别管他们，我才是重点
Don't worry about them, worry about me.
保罗，我的幕僚中 有很多职位还空着K
Paul, there are still positions in my administration that need to be filled,,,
包括幕僚长 我希望由你担任
,,, including chief of staff, I want that to be you,
等我到芝加哥 我们当面谈谈
When I get to Chicago, we'll meet and we'll talk.
钱全交出来
All of it.
我只带了买三明治的钱 我就坐在那里
Man, I just brought enough to get a sandwich. I was sitting right there.
如果你说谎K
If you're lying...
我女儿生病了 我很想赶快离开
Look, my daughter is sick and I don't wanna spend any more minutes in here.
相信我，我的钱都给你了
Trust me, that is all that I have.
你有多少钱，甜心？
What do you got, sweetheart?
有多少？
What do you got?
-你不想乖乖听话是吗？ -别激动
- You don't want to listen? - Hey. Hey, calm down, man.
-闭嘴！ -好
- Shut up. - All right.
听我说，请你冷静一点
Listen to me. You've got to calm down.
你要什么我都可以帮你
I can help you get everything that you want.
但你不想伤害任何人，对吧？
But you don't want to hurt anybody else, right?
别这样
Come on.
你听好
Look, listen. Hey.
你何不把门上锁 把休息的招牌翻过来
Why don't you lock the door and turn the closed sign back...
大家就以为 餐厅关门了，好吗？
...so everybody thinks that this place is closed, all right?
然后让所有人远离窗户
And then we can get everybody away from the window.
没意见吧？ 大家不要靠近窗户
Is that cool? Everybody's away from the window.
大家移到餐厅另一头
Let's move everybody on to this side of the room.
各位，过来这里 不要靠近窗户
Get on this side. Let's move to this side of the room, away from the window.
各位过去 餐厅另一头，好吗？
Let's get on this side of the room, okay?
餐厅这一边 你带我的女儿走，好吗？
This side of the room. Why don't you take my daughter, okay?
带她到餐厅里面K 不会有事的
Take her on this side of the room so that everybody, everything is gonna be okay.
不会有事的
Everything is gonna be fine.
因为你不会 再伤害任何人，对吧？
Because you're not gonna put your hand on another person, right?
好，一切都很好
Right. We're all good.
满意吧？
You all good?
没事了，对吧？
We're good, right?
-莎拉 -进来
- Hey, sara. - Come on in.
我刚才坐在这儿一直想
I've been sitting here, evaluating.
我在保释期间脱逃 现在正在逃亡
I jumped bail, I'm on the run...
我刚刚还企图杀人
...and I just tried to take a man's life.
我没有吸毒
I'm not using.
这其实是一大成就
Which is actually quite an accomplishment.
但三个礼拜前 我还是个医生
But three weeks ago, I was a doctor.
你可以找回你的人生
You can get that back.
全部找回来
All of it.
你要有这种信念
You need to believe that.
你有这种信念吗？
You believe that?
你觉得你可以 找回你的人生？
You think you can get it all back?
我选择抱持信念
I choose to have faith.
因为失去信念 我就一无所有
Because without that, I have nothing.
这是唯一让我活下去的力量
It's the only thing that's keeping me going.
这样啊
Well.
我有两件事 给我力量活下去
I got two things keeping me going.
第一是我要替父亲报仇
The first is that I want the people who took my dad.
至于第二件事K
And actually the second...
讽刺地是 我应该还没有失去
...ironically, I probably wouldn't even say if I hadn't lost it.
不过K
But...
你应该知道K
...you should know that...
接下这工作后 他们给我的第一个警告
The first thing they tell you when you take the job is...
就是千万不要爱上犯人
...never to fall in love with an inmate.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
路障
Roadblock.
林克，门锁住了
Linc, it's locked.
你不能进来这里！
Hey, you can't be in here.
-把路障撞开 -我办不到
- Run the roadblock. - Man, I can't do that.
撞过去
Run it.
（动力/加速器）
停车！
Hey, hold them up!
（州警）
布拉德贝里克，调查局
Bradley Bellick, FBI.
布拉德贝里克，联邦调查局
Brad Bellick, Federal Bureau of Investigation.
布拉德贝里克，调查局
Brad Bellick, FBI.
特别探员布拉德贝里克 调查局
Special Agent Brad Bellick, FBI.
你好，我是调查局的 布拉德贝里克
Hi, there. I'm Brad Bellick with the FBI.
我是调查局探员 布拉德贝里克
I'm an agent with the FBI, Brad Bellick.
布拉德贝里克 我是调查局的
Brad Bellick. I'm with the Bureau.
我能说的 都已经跟警察说过了
I already talked to the cops. Told them all I had to say.
我可不是地方小警察 我是联邦探员
Yeah, well, I'm no local hayseed cop. I'm federal.
你要是说谎 我可不会放过你
And you're not gonna get away with lying to me.
-我没有骗任何人 -真的吗？
- I didn't lie to nobody. - Really?
他只是个游民 常在汉卡广场闲晃K
"He was just some homeless guy. Hangs around Hancock square...
跟大学生要零钱 他一直待在那里
...hitting up college kids for change. He's down there all the time.
如果他不在 我也不知他在哪儿
If he's not there, I don't know where to find him."
-这就是你的口供？ -差不多
- That's your statement? - Pretty much.
不过有个问题，查尔斯帕托西克 绰号疯仔，是个偏执狂
Well, you see the problem is, Charles "Haywire" Patoshik's a paranoid...
他有人群恐惧症 他怕陌生人
...who suffers from fear of crowds, who's terrified of strangers.
所以他一定会躲在偏僻的地方 低调地独自当怪人
If he's anywhere, it's the middle of nowhere, keeping to himself, being a weirdo.
-所以呢？ -你想耍狠是吗？
- And? - And if you want to get tough...
不如我以妨碍办案 现在就逮捕你好吗？
...how about I arrest you right now for hindering a federal investigation?
他们会相信谁？
Who they gonna believe?
有十五年资历 和三次总统表扬的探员
An agent with 15 years on the force and three presidential citations...
还是有前科的低下阶层少女？
...or a piece of white trash with a juvie record?
我没有要求他动手
I didn't ask him to do it.
但如果你还没发现 我爸的死我一点也不难过
But in case you haven't noticed, I ain't exactly broken up over my dad's death.
你们为何 一定要找到帕托西克？
Why can't you just leave this Patoshik guy alone?
他在哪里？
Where is he?
还是你想现在就被关起来？
Or do you want to get locked up right now?
-请说 -我有帕托西克的线索
- Yeah? - I got a lead on Patoshik.
在哪里？
Where?
我马上过去
I'm on my way.
让他留在原地
Keep him there,
一个人
Alone.
有斯科菲尔德和柏劳的消息 我要立刻知道
Any information on scofield and Burrows, I want to be notified immediately.
如果你没意见的话
If that works out for you.
下一个车站 一定有警察等着我们
They're gonna have cops waiting for us at the next station.
-我们得跳车 -然后呢？
- We need to jump, then. - And do what?
躲在桶子底下？
Hide under a barrel?
林克说的对
Linc's right.
把东西放进去
Okay, just put those in there.
我真的很抱歉
So sorry about all this.
没事的，甜心
It's okay, sweetpea.
东西都在里面，老兄
Here's everything right here, man.
-没事了 -好
- It's good. - All right.
所有人立刻进仓库里
Everyone in the storage room. Now.
什么？
What?
到后面去，等警察来
Get back there, until the cops show up.
不K我不能进去
No, no, no, no. I can't go back there.
-我们走吧 -不行
- Come on. - No.
你一直都很冷静 现在别害死自己
You kept a cool head this whole time, don't get yourself killed.
你听好了
You know what? Listen to me.
我是个通缉犯
I'm a wanted man.
知道吗？
Okay?
警察来，我会被关回监狱 那我还无所谓
The police show up here, they'll take me back to prison. You know what? That's fine.
可是我的小女儿生病了
But my little girl right here, she's sick...
到时她会无依无靠
...and she's gonna be left alone.
我不能让这种事发生
And I can't let that happen.
所以拜托你让我们走好吗？
So can you please let us go?
-走吧 -好
- Split. - Okay.
-快走 -甜心，我们走
- Go on. - Come on, sweetie, let's go.
所有人到后面去，快点
All right, everyone in the back. Move.
你不能走
Not you.
你要跟我走
You're coming with me.
快进去
Go on, move.
你乖乖留在这里好吗？
Look, I want you to stay right here, okay?
-进去 -等等
- Go on. - Hey.
-你最好放开她 -快滚，这是最后一次机会
- I think you should let her go, man. - Take off. Last chance.
你已经抢到钱了
You got the money...
抢劫和攻击罪 那只是小罪，关一下就出来了
...burglary and assault, man. Hey, that's change, that's little time.
但你现在的行为？
But this right here?
你会终生出不了监狱 你最好相信我
You will be in prison for the rest of your life. You believe me on that.
如果你不想让女儿 看见你惨死K
Unless you want your daughter to see you die...
就快滚
...move.
我是在帮助你
I'm trying to help you, man.
过来！
Come here!
甜心，不要过来
Sweetie, stay right there.
糟了
Oh, no.
是谁揍他的？
Who did this?
是我
I did.
谢谢你
Thank you.
疯仔！
Haywire.
不准动！
Don't move.
赖瑞，快跑！快跑！
Run, Larry, run. Run, run.
迪诺，是我艾瑞克 有四人跳车
Dino, it's Eric, We got four jumpers,
三男一女 马上报告，行驶到下个车站
Three males and a female, call it in and get to the next station,
听到没？ 快载我们到下一站
Do you hear me? Get us to the next station,
撞开路障的人跳下车了
The men who pushed the roadblock are off the train...
约在五十四里路标处 刚过泰德福桥的南方
...near mile marker 54 just south of the Tedford Bridge.
我们是州警 留在原地不准动
This is the state police, Stop, Stop where you are,
-不准动！ -不要开枪！
- Freeze. - Don't shoot.
不要开枪！
Don't shoot.
转过来
Turn around.
我是火车公司的员工
I'm an employee of the train company.
迪诺，是我艾瑞克 有四人跳车
Dino, it's Eric. We got four jumpers.
三男一女 马上报告，行驶到下个车站
Three males and a female. Get us to the next station.
下去，快点
Let's go. Come on.
他们叫我们跳车然后逃跑 不准回头，不然他们会开枪
They told us to jump and run and not to look back, or they'd shoot us.
我们得找辆车
We need to find a car.
请说
Yeah?
我把疯仔困住了
I got Haywire trapped.
先别轻举妄动
Don't do anything,
在我赶到前牵制他
Just hold him till I get there.
没问题，这疯子被我困在高处
No problem. I got this wing nut treed.
-卡洛琳 -保罗，你在哪里？
- Caroline. - Paul, where are you?
-是你派警察来的吗？ -当然不是
- Did you send the police? - No, of course not,
-警方怎么知道我在火车上？ -保罗，我完全不知情
- How did they know I was on that train? - Paul, I have no idea,
-我会通知总统 -我会直接跟总统联络
- I'll let the president know. - I contact the president directly.
柏劳和斯科菲尔德 和你在一起吗？
Are Burrows and Scofield with you?
我以为我要向总统简报
I was expecting to brief the president.
现在起你向我回报
You report to me now.
保罗？
Paul?
我们在哪里度过 我三十五岁生日的？
Where did we spend my 35th birthday?
什么？
What?
那家餐厅，在哪里？ 你记得的
The restaurant, where was It? You remember.
别说傻话，我要走了
Don't be ridiculous. I have to go.
-不要挂电话 -我得走了
- Do not hang up. - I have to go.
-快逮捕那两兄弟 -喂
- Just get Burrows and Scofield, - Hey.
不管你是谁K
Whoever this is...
告诉比尔金 他这次搞砸了K
...tell Bill Kim that he just screwed up...
真的搞砸了
...big time.
保罗？
Paul?
这是怎么回事？
What's all this?
有疯子爬上 谷物升降机的顶端
Some wacko climbed to the top of a grain elevator.
人们就会来凑热闹
People wanna watch.
天啊，你应该控制好场面 你知道这是什么意思吗？
God, you were supposed to keep a handle on it. Do you know what that means?
我帮你逮到疯仔了 你还想怎样？
I got you Haywire. What else do you want?
调查局，他是我的犯人
FBI. He's my chargee.
你好吗，查尔斯？
How you doing, Charles?
我不想回监狱
I don't wanna go back to prison.
这我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我想去荷兰
I wanna go to Holland.
没想到你会这么说
That's not what I expected to hear.
但你不能去，孩子
But you can't go there, son.
我K
I just...
我只想去这个地方
I just want to go here.
看到了吗？
See?
不如这样吧
I'll tell you what.
你不必回监狱
You don't have to go to prison.
但你也不能去荷兰
But you can't go to Holland either.
不要K
Oh, no, no, no...
没事的K
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay. Hey.
你现在处境艰难
You're in a tough spot.
你觉得被困住 没有后路可退
You feel trapped, you got no options...
你遇到一个 自己无法掌控的状况
...and you're caught in a situation where you have no control.
我感同身受
I know how you feel.
真的
I do.
这状况让你心神不宁 你只想逃走
It takes its toll on you, and all you want to do is run.
可是能逃到哪儿？
But run where?
我只想离开
I just want to go.
有一个出路
There's a way out.
出路？
A way out?
走出这个迷宫？
Of this maze?
对
Yeah.
（伊利诺州，芝加哥）
后面有私人恒温箱 箱子上有会员的名字
There are private humidors in the back, each member's name is on their box.
-有警卫吗？ -只有一名接待员
- Any security? - A receptionist, that's it.
我不是通缉要犯
I'm not a wanted fugitive.
把钥匙给我，我去开
Give me the key. I'll do it.
你想去走走吗？
Want to take a walk?
好
Yeah.
我知道你父母伤害你 你才会杀他们
I know you killed your parents because they hurt you.
我也知道昨天你杀了那个人 是因为他伤害莎夏
And I know you killed that guy because he was hurting sasha, but what you did...
但那是不对的 你很清楚
...was wrong, you know that.
我只想离开
I just wanna go.
你可以
You can.
我现在就要走
I wanna go now.
没关系的
It's okay.
莎拉
Sara.
关于你之前说的事K
About before.
我也是
Me too.
好
Yeah.